One of the exciting things about a large language model is you could use it to
大型语言模型的一个令人兴奋之处在于您可以使用它来
build a custom chatbot with only a modest amount of effort.
仅需适度的努力就可以构建一个定制的聊天机器人。
ChatGPT, the web interface,
ChatGPT，即Web界面，
is a way for you to have a conversational interface,
是一种让您拥有会话式界面的方法，
a conversation via a large language model.
通过大型语言模型进行对话。
But one of the cool things is you can also use
但有趣的是，您还可以使用
a large language model to build your custom chatbot to maybe play the role of
大型语言模型来构建您的定制聊天机器人，它可能扮演
an AI customer service agent or an AI order taker for restaurants.
AI客服代表或餐厅AI接单员的角色。
In this video, you learn how to do that for yourself.
在这个视频中，您将学习如何为自己做到这一点。
I'm going to describe the components of
我将详细描述
the OpenAI chat completions format in more detail,
OpenAI聊天补全格式的组成部分，
and then you're going to build a chatbot yourself.
然后您将自己构建一个聊天机器人。
So let's get into it.
那么，让我们开始吧。
So first, we'll set up the OpenAI Python package as usual.
首先，我们将像往常一样设置OpenAI Python软件包。
So chat models like ChatGPT are actually trained to take a series of
实际上，像ChatGPT这样的聊天模型经过训练后可以接受一系列
messages as input and return a model-generated message as output.
将消息作为输入并返回模型生成的消息作为输出。
So although the chat format is designed to make
尽管聊天格式的设计目的是为了让
multi-turn conversations like this easy,
像这样的多轮对话变得简单，
we've seen through the previous videos that it's also just as
从之前的视频中我们也看到，同样地，
useful for single-turn tasks without any conversation.
它对于不需要对话的单轮任务也非常有用。
So next, we're going to define two helper functions.
接下来，我们将定义两个辅助函数。
So this is the one that we've been using throughout all the videos,
这是我们在所有视频中一直使用的一个，
and it's the get_Completion function.
它就是get_Completion函数。
But if you look at it,
但如果你仔细观察，
we give a prompt but then inside the function,
我们提供了一个提示，但在函数内部，
what we're actually doing is putting this prompt into
实际上我们在做的是将这个提示放入
what looks like some user message.
看起来像是某个用户消息。
This is because the ChatGPT model is a chat model,
这是因为ChatGPT模型是一个聊天模型，
which means it's trained to take a series of messages as input,
这意味着它被训练成将一系列消息作为输入，
and then return model-generated messages output.
然后返回模型生成的消息输出。
So the user message is the input,
所以用户消息是输入，
and then the assistant message is the output.
然后助手消息是输出。
So in this video,
所以在这个视频中，
we're going to actually use a different helper function,
我们实际上将使用一个不同的辅助函数，
and instead of putting a single prompt as input and getting a single completion,
而不是将单个提示作为输入并获得单个补全，
we're going to pass in a list of messages,
我们将传入一系列消息，
and these messages can be from a variety of different roles.
这些消息可以来自不同的角色。
So I'll describe those.
接下来我会详细描述。
So here's an example of a list of messages.
这里有一个消息列表的例子。
So the first message is a system message,
首先是一个系统消息，
which gives an overall instruction.
它给出了总体指示。
Then after this message,
在这条消息之后，
we have turns between the user and the assistant,
用户和助手之间会进行轮流，
and this will continue to go on.
这将继续进行。
If you've ever used ChatGPT,
如果您曾经使用过ChatGPT，
the web interface, then your messages are the user messages,
Web界面中，您的消息就是用户消息，
and then ChatGPT's messages are the assistant messages.
然后ChatGPT的消息就是助手消息。
So the system message helps to set the behavior and persona of the assistant,
系统消息有助于设定助手的行为和角色，
and it acts as a high-level instruction for the conversation.
它充当对话的高级指示。
So you can think of it as whispering in
你可以把它想象成在
the assistant's ear and guiding its responses
助手的耳边低语并引导它的回应，
without the user being aware of the system message.
而用户并不知道这个系统消息。
So as the user,
所以作为用户，
if you've ever used ChatGPT,
如果您曾经使用过ChatGPT，
you probably don't know what's in ChatGPT's system message,
您可能不知道ChatGPT的系统消息中有什么，
and that's the intention.
这就是设计的初衷。
The benefit of the system message is that it provides you,
系统消息的好处在于它为您提供了，
the developer, with a way to frame
作为开发者，一个构建
the conversation without making the request itself part of the conversation.
对话的方式，而无需让请求本身成为对话的一部分。
So you can guide the assistant and whisper in
因此，您可以引导助手并低语在
its ear and guide its responses without making the user aware.
耳边引导它的回应，而不让用户察觉。
So now let's try to use these messages in a conversation.
那么现在让我们尝试在对话中使用这些消息。
So we'll use our new helper function to get the completion from the messages,
我们将使用新的辅助函数从消息中获取补全内容，
and we're also using a higher temperature.
同时，我们还使用了更高的“随机性参数”。
So the system message says,
所以系统消息说，
"You're an assistant that speaks like Shakespeare."
“你是一个说话像莎士比亚的助手。”
So this is us describing to the assistant how it should behave,
这是我们向助手描述它应该如何表现，
and then the first user message is, "Tell me a joke."
然后第一个用户消息是，“给我讲个笑话。”
The next is, "Why did the chicken cross the road?"
接下来是，“鸡为什么过马路？”
Then the final user message is, "I don't know."
然后最后一条用户消息是，“我不知道。”
So if we run this,
所以，如果我们运行这个，
the response is to get to the other side. Let's try again.
回应是“为了到达另一边”。我们再试一次。
"To get to the other side,
“为了到达另一边，
Fair sir or madam," it is an old and classic that never fails.
公平的先生或女士，”这是一句古老且经典的、永不过时的话。
So that's our Shakespearean response.
所以这就是我们的莎士比亚式回应。
Let's actually try one more thing,
实际上，让我们再尝试一件事，
because I want to make it even clearer that this is the assistant message.
因为我想更清楚地表明这是助手消息。
So here let's just go and print the entire message response.
所以在这里，我们只需打印整个消息回应。
So just to make this even clearer,
所以为了让这更清楚，
this response is an assistant message.
这个回应是一个助手消息。
So the role is assistant and then the content is the message itself.
所以角色是助手，然后内容就是消息本身。
So that's what's happening in this helper function.
所以这就是这个辅助函数中发生的事情。
We're just passing out the content of the message.
我们只是传递消息的内容。
So now let's do another example.
所以现在让我们做另一个例子。
So here our messages are,
所以这里我们的消息是，
the system message is,
系统消息是，
"You're a friendly chatbot," and the first user message is,
“你是一个友好的聊天机器人，”第一个用户消息是，
"Hi, my name is Isa."
“嗨，我叫Isa。”
We want to get the first user message.
我们想获得第一个用户消息。
So let's execute this,
那么让我们执行这个，
the first assistant message.
第一个助手消息。
So the first message is,
所以第一条消息是，
"Hello, Isa. It's nice to meet you.
“你好，Isa。很高兴认识你。
How can I assist you today?"
今天我能帮助你做什么？”
Now let's try another example.
现在我们来试试另一个例子。
So here our messages are,
所以这里我们的消息是，
system message, "You're a friendly chatbot," and the first user message is,
系统消息，“你是一个友好的聊天机器人，”第一个用户消息是，
"Yes, can you remind me what is my name?"
“是的，你能提醒我，我的名字是什么吗？”
Let's get the response.
让我们看看回应。
As you can see, the model doesn't actually know my name.
如你所见，模型实际上不知道我的名字。
So each conversation with a language model is a standalone interaction,
所以与语言模型的每次对话都是独立的互动，
which means that you must provide all relevant messages
这意味着您必须提供所有相关消息
for the model to draw from in the current conversation.
以便模型在当前对话中获取信息。
If you want the model to draw from or "remember" earlier parts of a conversation,
如果您希望模型从之前的对话中获取或“记住”信息，
you must provide the earlier exchanges in the input to the model.
您必须在输入模型中提供之前的交流内容。
So we'll refer to this as context.
所以我们把这称为上下文。
So let's try this.
那我们试试吧。
So now we've given the context that the model needs,
现在我们已经提供了模型所需的上下文，
which is my name in the previous messages,
就是之前消息中的我的名字，
and we'll ask the same question.
然后我们将问同样的问题。
So we'll ask what my name is,
所以我们会问我的名字是什么，
and the model is able to respond because it has all of the context it
模型能够回应，因为它具备了所有的上下文，
needs in this list of messages that we input to it.
我们输入给它的这些消息列表中的内容。
So now you're going to build your own chatbot.
所以现在你将要构建自己的聊天机器人。
This chatbot is going to be called orderbot,
这个聊天机器人将被称为orderbot，
and we're going to automate the collection of
我们将自动收集
user prompts and assistant responses in order to build this orderbot.
用户提示和助手回应以构建这个orderbot。
It's going to take orders at a pizza restaurant.
它将在一个披萨餐厅接受订单。
So first, we're going to define this helper function.
首先，我们要定义这个辅助函数。
What this is doing is it's going to collect our user messages,
这个函数将收集我们的用户消息，
so we can avoid typing them in by hand in the way that we did above.
这样我们就可以避免像上面那样手动输入它们。
This is going to collect the prompts from a user interface that we'll build below,
这将从我们下面要构建的用户界面中收集提示，
and then append it to a list called context,
然后将其添加到一个叫做context的列表中，
and then it will call the model with that context every time.
然后每次都会用那个上下文调用模型。
The model response is then also added to the context.
然后模型响应也会被添加到上下文中。
So the model message is added to the context,
所以模型消息被添加到上下文中，
the user message is added to the context,
用户消息被添加到上下文中，
so on, so it just grows longer and longer.
依此类推，所以它会变得越来越长。
This way, the model has the information it needs to determine what to do next.
这样，模型就具备了决定接下来要做什么的所需信息。
So now we'll set up and run this UI to display the orderbot.
现在我们将设置并运行这个UI来显示orderbot。
So here's the context,
这里是上下文，
and it contains the system message that contains the menu.
它包含了包含菜单的系统消息。
Note that every time we call the language model,
注意，每次我们调用语言模型，
we're going to use the same context,
我们都将使用相同的上下文，
and the context is building up over time.
并且随着时间的推移，上下文在不断累积。
Then let's execute this.
那么我们来执行这个。
I'm going to say,
我要说，
"Hi, I would like to order a pizza."
“嗨，我想订一份披萨。”
The assistant says, "Great.
助手说，“太好了。
What pizza would you like to order?
您想要订哪种披萨？
We have pepperoni, cheese, and eggplant pizza."
我们有意大利辣香肠、奶酪和茄子披萨。”
How much are they?
它们多少钱？
Great. Okay, we have the prices.
好的。好，我们有价格了。
I think I'm feeling a medium eggplant pizza.
我想要一份中份茄子披萨。
So as you can imagine,
所以如您所想，
we could continue this conversation.
我们可以继续这个对话。
Let's look at what we've put in the system message.
让我们看看我们在系统消息里加了什么。
So you are orderbot,
所以你是orderbot，
an automated service to collect orders for a pizza restaurant.
一个为披萨餐厅收集订单的自动化服务。
You first greet the customer,
您首先要向顾客问候，
then collect the order,
然后收集订单，
and then ask if it's a pickup or delivery.
接着询问是自取还是送货。
You wait to collect the entire order,
您等待收集整个订单，
then summarize it and check for a final time
然后总结并最后确认一次
if the customer wants to add anything else.
顾客是否还想添加其他东西。
If it's a delivery, you can ask for an address.
如果是送货，您可以询问地址。
Finally, you collect the payment.
最后，您收取付款。
Make sure to clarify all options,
确保澄清所有选项，
extras, and sizes to uniquely identify the item from the menu.
附加选项和尺寸，以便从菜单中唯一识别该项。
You respond in a short, very conversational, friendly style.
您以简短、非常对话式、友好的风格回应。
The menu includes, and then here we have the menu.
菜单包括，然后我们在这里有菜单。
So let's go back to our conversation,
那么让我们回到我们的对话，
and let's see if the assistant has been following the instructions.
看看助手是否遵循了指示。
Okay, great. The assistant asks if we want any toppings,
好的，很好。助手询问我们是否需要任何配料，
which we specified in the system message.
这是我们在系统消息中指定的。
So I think we want no extra toppings.
所以我认为我们不需要额外的配料。
Sure thing.
没问题。
Is there anything else we'd like to order?
我们还想要点别的吗？
Let's get some water.
来点水吧。
Actually, fries.
实际上，要薯条。
Small or large?
小份还是大份？
This is great because we asked the assistant in
这很好，因为我们在
the system message to clarify extras and sides.
系统消息中要求助手澄清附加选项和配菜。
You get the idea, and please feel free to play with this yourself.
你明白了，欢迎自由地尝试一下。
You can pause the video and just go ahead and
您可以暂停视频，然后继续
run this in your own notebook on the left.
在左边的笔记本中运行这个。
Now we can ask the model to create
现在我们可以要求模型创建
a JSON summary that we could
一个我们可以
send to the order system based on the conversation.
根据对话发送给订单系统的JSON摘要。
So we're now appending another system message,
所以现在我们要追加另一个系统消息，
which is an instruction,
这是一个指令，
and we're saying, create a JSON summary of the previous food order,
我们说，创建一个之前食物订单的JSON摘要，
itemize the price for each item.
列出每项的价格。
The fields should be one pizza,
字段应该包括一份披萨，
include side, two list of toppings,
包括边料，两种配料清单，
three lists of drinks,
三种饮料清单，
and four list of sides,
还有四种配菜清单，
and finally the total price.
最后是总价格。
You could also use a user message here.
这里您也可以使用用户消息。
This does not have to be a system message.
这不一定是一个系统消息。
So let's execute this.
那么让我们执行这个。
Notice in this case, we're using a lower temperature
注意，在这种情况下，我们使用较低的“随机性参数”
because for these kinds of tasks,
因为对于这些类型的任务，
we want the output to be fairly predictable.
我们希望输出相当可预测。
For a conversational agent,
对于一个会话代理，
you might want to use a higher temperature.
您可能需要使用更高的“随机性参数”。
However, in this case, I would maybe use a lower temperature as well,
然而，在这种情况下，我也可能使用较低的“随机性参数”，
because for a customer's assistant chatbot,
因为对于一个客户助手聊天机器人，
you might want the output to be a bit more predictable as well.
您可能希望输出也更加可预测。
So here we have the summary of our order,
所以这里我们有我们订单的摘要，
and so we could submit this to the order system if we wanted to.
因此，如果我们愿意，我们可以将此提交给订单系统。
So there we have it.
所以我们就有了它。
You've built your very own order chatbot.
您已经构建了自己的订购聊天机器人。
Feel free to customize it yourself and play around with the system message
随意自定义它，并尝试更改系统消息
to change the behavior of the chatbot
以改变聊天机器人的行为
and get it to act as different personas with different knowledge.
并让它扮演具有不同知识的不同角色。